Okay, I promised you some interaction
with the HTML page. The first one that
we're going to talk about is how you can
use um events that happen on the HTML
page to trigger your code. So to do
that, you would need some code to
trigger. So I'm going to write myself a
function here. I'm going to call it show
alert.
And inside I'm just going to say alert
hello world.
Okay,
right now this function isn't being
called. I've just defined it. In fact,
if we go live,
you can see that I didn't get any alert
popups. I am going to zoom this page in.
Um, so I've got a button and a text box.
And right now, neither of them do
anything.
Coming back over here, um,
we could make them do something. So, the
way it makes one of the HTML tags do
something is you attach an event to it.
The way you do that is you type the word
on and then these are all of the things
that you can do that can call a
function. So you can say I want to call
a function when they click on it. I want
to call a function when they double
click on it. Um but let's just start
with on click right now. In the
quotation marks you want to put the name
of the function that you want called and
parenthesis. What this says is it says
when they click this button that says
hello world I want you to show the
alert. So coming back over, we'll click
the button and we get the alert. So now
we've successfully attached a function
to our button, which means anything we
wrote in a function previously, we can
now attach that to a button as a
trigger. Okay. Well, let's see what
other triggers there are. Um, one of the
other fun ones is on
mouse enter. Um, so that means when the
mouse enters this, um, input field, um,
what do you want to do? And in this
case, I'm going to call that exact same
function called show alert. So, if I
come over, I can click hello world and I
get the alert. Or I could mouse into the
field and I get an alert that says hello
world.
Um, and there's a whole bunch of these
events. There's onkey down, on key
press, on key up. So you can read a
whole bunch of inputs and you can have
your code work based on those inputs.